Guide to the Ernesto Galarza Papers, 1936-1984
Department of Special Collections
- Organizational files, 1935-1974, Series 3
  - Subseries A: Agricultural Labor
    - Southern Tenant Farmers Union/National Farm Labor Union/ National Agricultural Workers Union, 1935-1972
      - NFLU/NAWU (California), 1947-1972
        - Correspondence, Jan.-Apr., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, May-June, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, July-Nov., 1960 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Financial records, 1949-1960 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Flyers and ephemera, ca. 1949-1959 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - History, H.L. Mitchell oral history transcript, 1956-1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - History, "The National Farm Labor Union in California: Background to Cesar Chavez," Donald H. Grubbs, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - History, 25th Anniversary Celebration; "Workers in Our Fields," 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - Labor's League for Political Education, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Minutes, 1949-1960 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Miscellany, 1950-1958 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        - Newsclippings, 1947-1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Newsclippings, 1952-1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Newsletters, "El Porvenir," "Organizador del Campo," 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Newspapers, "Farm Labor News," "The Agricultural Unionist," 1946-1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Notes, 1948-1960 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - Press releases, 1949-1960 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Statements and reports, 1947-1952 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Statements and reports, 1953-1958 (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Statements and reports, 1959-1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Valley Organizing Committee, minutes, 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - NFLU/NAWU (Louisiana), 1951-1970
        - Louisiana Fruit and Vegetable Producers Union, Local 312, 1951-1957 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        - Repeal of "Right-to-Work" law, correspondence, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 2)
        - Repeal of "Right-to-Work" law, newsclippings, newsletters, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Repeal of "Right-to-Work" law, notes, legislative information, 1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - Repeal of "Right-to-Work" law, statements and reports, 1954-1956 (Box 10, Folder 5)
        - Sugar cane strike, newsclippings, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - Sugar cane strike, papers, 1964, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Other Farm Labor Organizations, 1937-1973
      - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - American Friends Service Committee, Farm Labor Project, 1954-1956, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - California Agricultural Workers Union, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - California Citizens Committee for Agricultural Labor, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - California Labor Federation, AFL-CIO, press releases and newsletters, 1950-1965 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - California Labor Federation, AFL-CIO, statements and reports, 1937-1965 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - California Migrant Ministry/National Farm Worker Ministry, 1959-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - California Rural Legal Assistance, 1966-1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Citizens for Farm Labor, 1963-1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Citizens for Farm Labor, "Farm Labor" (newsletter), 1963-May, 1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Citizens for Farm Labor, "Farm Labor" (newsletter), July-Dec., 1964 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Distributive, Processing and Office Workers of America, Local 78, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Emergency Committee to Aid Farm Workers, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Information Committee on Public Law 78, 1963-1964 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous organizations, 1950-1964 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - National Advisory Committee on Farm Labor, 1958-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - National Citizens Council on Migrant Labor, 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor, 1950-1960 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - National Farm Workers Association/United Farm Workers Organizing Committee/United Farm Workers, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor, 1967-1971 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - National Council on Agricultural Life and Labor, newsclippings and articles, 1966-1970 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - National Sharecroppers Fund, correspondence, 1947-1962 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - National Sharecroppers Fund, minutes, 1956-1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - National Sharecroppers Fund, reports, 1948-1962 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Regional Foreign Labor Operations Advisory Committee, 1954-1960 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - South Santa Clara County Interfaith Migrant Committee, 1964-1965 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Teamsters Union, 1948-1964 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - United Packinghouse Workers of America, AFL-CIO, 1951-1958 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - United Packinghouse Workers of America, AFL-CIO, 1959-1967 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Subseries B: Other Organizations, 1939-1974
    - American Council of Spanish-Speaking People, "Civil Liberties Newsletter," 1951-1953 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - American G.I. Forum, 1953-1970 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - American G.I. Forum, The Forumeer, 1953-1971 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bishops Committee for the Spanish Speaking, 1958, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Cabinet Committee on Opportunities for Spanish Speaking People, 1967-1974 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Chicano Law Students Association, Stanford Law School, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Community Service Organization, 1949-1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Community Service Organization, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - El Congreso de Pueblos de Habla Espanola, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Fair Employment Practices Commission, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Guadalupe Organization (Arizona), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Inter-Agency Committee on Mexican-American Affairs, 1967-1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - La Raza Unida (national, state, local), 1967-1973 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Mexican-American Community Services Agency, 1964-1974 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., by-laws, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., certificate of incorporation, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., memoranda, 1970-1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., miscellany, 1967-1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., newsletters, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Mexican-American Legal Defense and Educational Fund, Inc., reports, 1971-1974 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Mexican-American Movement, Inc., 1944 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Mexican American organizations, Alameda County/Oakland, 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Mexican-American Political Association, correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Mexican-American Political Association, newsletters and newsclippings, 1964-1968 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Mexican-American Political Association, statements and reports, 1963-1967 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Mexican-American Study Project, University of California, Los Angeles, 1964-1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, A-J, 1965-1972 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, M-Y, 1964-1974 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - National Council of La Raza, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Neighborhood Youth Corps, Ventura County, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Southern Alameda Spanish Speaking Organization, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Southwest Council of La Raza, 1966-1971 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - United States Catholic Conference, Division for the Spanish-Speaking, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - United States Commission on Civil Rights, staff reports on Mexican Americans, 1962-1967 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Subject files, 1923-1978, Series 4
  Galarza's subject files are also divided into agricultural and non-agricultural sub-series. Major topics within the former include braceros, court cases, crops, the DiGiorgio Fruit Corporation, and agriculture by geographical location. One of the most important topics documented by these papers is the bracero labor system, mandated by Public Law 78 (1951), which was viewed by NAWU as one of the primary obstacles in its attempt to organize domestic farm labor. The strict provisions of P.L. 78 regarding food, housing, wages and working conditions proved difficult to enforce, and Galarza gathered all the data he could on grower abuses. Since the ready availability of bracero labor greatly hampered NAWU's ability to extract concessions from growers, the union became a leader in the struggle to repeal P.L. 78. Galarza's bracero files are divided into two categories. The first reflects his investigation into living and working conditions. Correspondence, reports, interview notes, contracts, and paystubs were used by him to substantiate his charge that braceros faced systematic exploitation. The second, more extensive category documents the contract labor policies and positions of various organizations, including NAWU, the AFL-CIO, and the Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee. The files contain Galarza's correspondence with H.L. Mitchell concerning NAWU's anti-bracero strategy and his correspondence with labor leaders such as Frank L. Noakes, an official in the Railroad Workers Union and Director of the U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee. Galarza also collected material on the positions of Mexican labor unions, the Catholic Church, and growers toward P.L. 78. There is a considerable amount of material on the state and federal agencies charged with the administration of the bracero program (for instance, the Bureau of Employment Security of the U.S. Department of Labor and the Farm Placement Service of the California Department of Employment). Files on these agencies contain material relating to their operation and administration. Correspondence between NAWU and the Farm Placement Service, the office of the governor, and other state agencies is also included. Records pertaining to NAWU's and Galarza's confrontation with the DiGiorgio Fruit Corporation form a separate unit within the agriculture-related subject file. These conflicts began with the 1947-1950 strike and continued into the mid-1960s with suits and countersuits in California courts. After NAWU merged with Amalgamated in 1960, Galarza and his attorney, James Murray, countersued DiGiorgio Corporation for libel. Records in the DiGiorgio Fruit Corporation and DiGiorgio Fruit Corporation--Court Cases sections include correspondence, reports, strike bulletins, press releases, legal documents, notes and newsclippings. An important section under agricultural labor is Geographical Locations, which includes information gathered by Galarza while organizing from Yuba and Sutter counties north of Sacramento to Imperial County on the U.S.-Mexico border. Farm labor topics included in the collection are: crops, employment, growers, housing, immigration, migrants, "Right-to-Work" legislation (which prohibited the requirement of union membership as a conditon of employment), and wages. The main non-agricultural topics in Series IV are education of Mexican Americans and poverty programs in urban areas. The first focuses on Mexican American studies programs at colleges and universities and the Studio Laboratory for Bilingual Education, which Galarza founded and directed for the San Jose Unified School District. The Studio Lab papers reflect Galarza's philosophy of bilingual education and his concern that the students, faculty and community have input into the planning process. Galarza disagreed with Olivia Martinez, director of the San Jose Area Consortium for Bilingual Education, over how bilingual programs should be implemented and what curriculum materials should be used. After the Studio Lab was terminated in favor of the Consortium, Galarza started the Community Organization Monitoring Education as a citizen-watchdog group. In 1965 and 1966, Galarza was a program analyst for the Economic and Youth Opportunities Agency of Greater Los Angeles (EYOA). EYOA, a recipient of Community Action Program grants from the federal Office of Economic Opportunity, screened community group funding proposals and administered programs. Galarza gathered information on various minority-oriented economic and educational assistance programs which flourished in Los Angeles and other urban areas in the mid-1960s.
  - Subseries A: Agricultural Labor, 1923-1971
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, claims by families of the deceased, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, claims by injured, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, Congressman Charles Gubser, 1958-1963 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, newsclippings, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, notes and interviews, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Accidents on the job, Chualar Bus Accident, reports and legal documents, 1963-1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Accidents on the job, D'Arrigo, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Accidents on the job, correspondence, notes and reports, 1948-1953 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Accidents on the job, correspondence, notes and reports, 1954-1963 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Accidents on the job, newsclippings, 1949-1963 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Accidents on the job, safety standards for transporting workers, 1951-1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Accidents on the job, Visalia Bus Accident, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Anderson, Henry Pope, correspondence, 1958-1961 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Henry Pope, "Health Attitudes and Practices of Braceros, Report of Progress, Jan. 1-Dec. 31, 1957" (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Henry Pope, statements, 1958-1961 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Asian contract laborers, 1950-1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Asian contract laborers, newsclippings, 1950-1959 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Braceros (Conditions), 1943-1964
    - Correspondence, reports and statements, 1943-1944 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, reports and statements, 1945 (1) (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, reports and statements, 1945 (2) (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, notes and wage information, 1947-1954 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, notes and wage information, 1956-1964 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Deportations, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Field documents, 1950-1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Health care and insurance, 1952-1956 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Health care and insurance, 1957-1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Interview notes (by Galarza), 1953-Oct. 15, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Interview notes (by Galarza), Oct. 16, 1955-Dec., 1955 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Mexican Consular Service, documents, 1944-May, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Mexican Consular Service, documents, June-July, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Mexican Consular Service, documents, Aug.-Sept., 1945 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Wages, contracts, notes, 1952-1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Wages, paystubs, notes, 1951-1954 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Wages, paystubs, notes, 1955-1958 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Wages, statistical reports, 1957-1959 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Subseries C: Braceros (Policy), 1943-1967
    - Alianza de Braceros Nacionales de Mexico en los Estados Unidos de Norteamerica, correspondence (Alianza-NAWU), press releases, notes, 1949-1957 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Alianza de Braceros Nacionales de Mexico en los Estados Unidos de Norteamerica, correspondence (Alianza-NAWU), questionnaires given to braceros, ca. 1955 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - American Federation of Labor, correspondence, newsclippings, statements, 1950-1960 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations, newsclippings, press releases, statements, 1953-1966 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1949-1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1957 (1) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1957 (2) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1958 (1) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1958(2) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1959 (1) (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1959(2) (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, 1960-1962 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - California Dept. of Employment, Farm Placement Service, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - California state agencies, statistics on agricultural labor, 1943-1959 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - California, state agricultural policy, miscellany, newsclippings, 1946-1961 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Catholic organizations, addresses, publications, 1952-1958 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Congress of Industrial Organizations, 1952, 1955 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Growers, 1948-1960 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Growers, Steve Martinez, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee, correspondence, Joint Committee-U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1955-1958 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee, minutes, statements, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee, minutes, statements, 1955-1956 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee, minutes, statements, 1957-1958 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee, minutes, statements, 1959-1960, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Joint U.S.-Mexico Trade Union Committee,newsclippings, 1953-1957 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Mexican government, correspondence, statements, 1945-1951 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Mexican government, newsclippings, 1950-1951 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Mexican organizations, correspondence, organizations-NAWU, 1949-1957 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-California State, 1948-1953 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-California State, 1954-1958 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-California State, 1959-1960 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-Mexican officials, 1945-1955 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-U.S. Dept. of Justice, 1947-1958 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1950-1960 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-USDL, Bureau of Employment Security, 1948-Aug., 1952 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-USDL, Bureau of Employment Security, Sept., 1952-1960 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - NAWU, correspondence, NAWU-U.S. Dept. of State, 1945-1955 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - NAWU, inter-union, 1947-1948 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - NAWU, correspondence, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - NAWU, correspondence, 1950-May, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - NAWU, correspondence, Aug., 1951-Feb., 1952 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - NAWU, correspondence, Apr., 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - NAWU, correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - NAWU, correspondence, 1958 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - NAWU, correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - NAWU, correspondence, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - NAWU, petition on the importation of Mexican nationals, n.d. (1) (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - NAWU, petition on the importation of Mexican nationals, n.d. (2) (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - NAWU, statements, 1948-1952 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - NAWU,statements, 1953-1959, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - NAWU, union list of growers violating employment regulations, 1950 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - NAWU, U.S.-Mexican government negotiations, 1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - NAWU, wage determination, state and federal documents, 1949-1955 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - NAWU, wage determination, state and federal documents, 1956-1958, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1943 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1946 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1947 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1948 (1) (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1948(2) (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1950 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1951 (1) (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1951 (2) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Newsclippings, general,, 1952 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1954 (1) (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1954 (2) (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1954 (3) (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1955 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1956 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1957 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1958 (1) (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1958 (2) (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1959 (1) (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1959 (2) (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1960 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Newsclippings, general, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - U.S. Congress, correspondence, texts of bills, 1946-1964 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Congress, Congressional Record (excerpts), 1951-1959 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1942-1958 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, advisory committees, 1951-1961 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, correspondence, miscellany, 1948-1958 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor,correspondence, 1959-1963, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, foreign labor interpretations, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, migrant labor agreement and standard work contract, 1949-1959 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, newsclippings, 1958-1960 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, statements by senior administrators, 1952-1958 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, statements by senior administrators, 1959-1961 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, annual reports, 1952, 1956-1957 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, 1958-1960, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, correspondence, 1958-1962, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, division of responsibility with state employment agencies, 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, El Centro Reception Center, correspondence and statement, Eris Quinn, 1956-1958 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, "Farm Labor Market Developments," 1955-1959 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, manuals, minutes, news releases, 1950-1954 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - U.S. Dept. of Labor, Bureau of Employment Security, memos to field staff, 1952-1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)